<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<!--
  ~  Copyright (c) 2009, WSO2 Inc. (http://www.wso2.org) All Rights Reserved.
  ~
  ~  WSO2 Inc. licenses this file to you under the Apache License,
  ~  Version 2.0 (the "License"); you may not use this file except
  ~  in compliance with the License.
  ~  You may obtain a copy of the License at
  ~
  ~    http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0
  ~
  ~  Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing,
  ~  software distributed under the License is distributed on an
  ~  "AS IS" BASIS, WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY
  ~  KIND, either express or implied.  See the License for the
  ~  specific language governing permissions and limitations
  ~  under the License.
  -->

<!DOCTYPE html
        PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD XHTML 1.0 Transitional//EN"
        "http://www.w3.org/TR/xhtml1/DTD/xhtml1-strict.dtd">
<html xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xml:lang="en" lang="en">
    <head>
        <meta content="text/html; charset=iso-8859-1" http-equiv="content-type"/>
        <title>WSO2 EI v@product.version@ Released - April 2019</title>
    </head>
    <body>
        <div id="header">
        </div>

        <div id="main-content">
            <h1>The WSO2 Enterprise Integrator (EI) @product.version@ Released!</h1>

            <p>
                WSO2 EI team is pleased to announce the release of version @product.version@ of
                the Open Source Enterprise Integrator (EI).
            </p>

            <p>
                WSO2 EI is a unified distribution of WSO2 Enterprise Service Bus and
                Data Services Server, which works as a single runtime (Integrator) along with optional runtimes for
                EI Analytics, Business Processor and Message Broker. This product distribution includes a shared
                component directory, with profile-based management capabilities for each runtime.
            </p>

            <p>
                WSO2 EI simplifies integration by allowing users to easily configure message routing, message mediation,
                transformation, logging, task scheduling, load balancing, failover routing,
                event brokering etc. Data services and various applications can also be hosted and exposed using WSO2 EI.
                These integration capabilities are further powered by the capabilities of the EI Analytics, Business Processor and Message Broker runtimes.
            </p>


            <h2>Installation and Running </h2>
            <h3>Running the Integrator</h3>
            <ol>
                <li>Extract the downloaded wso2ei-@product.version@.zip</li>
                <li>Go to the bin directory in the extracted folder</li>
                <li>Run the integrator.sh or integrator.bat as appropriate</li>
                <li>Point your browser to the URL https://localhost:9443/carbon</li>
                <li>Use "admin", "admin" as the username and password to login as an admin</li>
                <li>If you need to start the OSGi console with the server use the property
                    -DosgiConsole when starting the server.</li>
            </ol>
            <h3>Running other runtimes individually (Analytics, Broker, Business Process )</h3>
            <ol>
                <li>Extract wso2ei-@product.version@.zip and go to the extracted directory.</li>
                <li>Go to wso2ei-@product.version@/wso2 directory.</li>
                <li>Go to appropriate runtime directory (analytics/broker/business-process) /bin.</li>
                <li> Execute wso2server.sh or wso2server.bat.</li>
            </ol>

            <h2>Key Features of WSO2 EI</h2>
            <ul>
                <li>Proxy services - facilitating synchronous/asynchronous transport, interface
                    (WSDL/Schema/Policy), message format (SOAP 1.1/1.2, POX/REST, Text, Binary),
                    QoS (WS-Addressing/WS-Security) and optimization switching (MTOM/SwA).</li>
                <li>API facilitating building REST APIs</li>
                <li>Non-blocking HTTP/S transports based on Apache HttpCore-NIO for ultra-fast
                    execution and support for thousands of connections at high concurrency with
                    constant memory usage.</li>
                <li>Built in Registry/Repository, facilitating dynamic updating and reloading
                    of the configuration and associated resources (e.g. XSLTs, XSD, WSDL,
                    Policies, JS configurations ..)</li>
                <li>Easily extendable via custom Java classes (mediator and command)/Spring
                    configurations, or BSF Scripting languages (Javascript, Ruby, Groovy, etc.)</li>
                <li>Built in support for scheduling tasks using the Quartz scheduler.</li>
                <li>Load-balancing (with or without sticky sessions)/Fail-over, and clustered
                    Throttling and Caching support</li>
                <li>WS-Security, Caching &amp; Throttling configurable via
                    (message/operation/service level) WS-Policies</li>
                <li>Lightweight, XML and Web services centric messaging model</li>
                <li> Support for industrial standards (Hessian binary web service protocol/
                    Financial Information eXchange protocol and optional Health Level-7 protocol)</li>
                <li>Enhanced support for the VFS (File/FTP/SFTP), JMS, Mail transports with
                    optional TCP/UDP transports and transport switching among any of the above
                    transports</li>
                <li>Support for message splitting &amp; aggregation using the EIP and service
                    callouts</li>
                <li>Database lookup &amp; store support with DBMediators with reusable database
                    connection pools</li>
                <li>WS-Eventing support</li>
                <li>Rule based mediation of the messages using the Drools rule engine</li>
                <li>Transactions support via the JMS transport and Transaction mediator for
                    database mediators</li>
                <li>Internationalized GUI management console with user management for
                    configuration development</li>
                <li>Integrated monitoring support with statistics, configurable logging and tracing</li>
                <li>JMX monitoring support and JMX management capabilities like,
                    Graceful/Forceful shutdown/restart</li>
                <li>Deploying Business Processes written in compliance with WS-BPEL 2.0 Standard and BPEL4WS 1.1 standard.</li>
                <li>Deploying Business Processes written in compliance with a frequently used subset of BPMN 2.0 standard.</li>
                <li>Support for Human Interactions in BPEL Processes with WS-Human Task and BPEL4People.</li>
                <li>Comprehensive and customizable web applications for managing human tasks. bpmn processes and
                    instances</li>

            </ul>


            <h2>Known Issues</h2>
            <p>
                All the open issues pertaining to WSO2 EI @product.version@ are reported at following
                locations:
            </p>
            <ul>
                <li><a href="https://github.com/wso2/product-ei/issues">
                    WSO2 EI @product.version@ component issues</a></li>
            </ul>

            <h2>How You Can Contribute</h2>
            <h3>
                Mailing Lists
            </h3>
            <p>
                Join our mailing list and correspond with the developers directly.
            </p>
            <ul>
                <li>
                    Developer List : <a href="mailto:dev@wso2.org">dev@wso2.org</a>
                    | <a href="mailto:dev-request@wso2.org?subject=subscribe">Subscribe</a>
                    | <a href="http://mail.wso2.org/mailarchive/dev/">Mail Archive</a>
                </li>
            </ul>
            <h3>
                Reporting Issues
            </h3>
            <p>
                We encourage you to report issues, documentation faults and feature requests regarding
                WSO2 EI through the public <a href="https://github.com/wso2/product-ei/issues">Github EI issues</a>.
            </p>

            <h3>
                Discussion Forums
            </h3>
            <p>
                Alternatively, questions could be raised on <a href="http://stackoverflow.com/questions/tagged/wso2">http://stackoverflow.com</a>.
            </p>

            <h2>Support</h2>
            <p>
                We are committed to ensuring that your enterprise middleware deployment is
                completely supported from evaluation to production. Our unique approach
                ensures that all support leverages our open development methodology and is
                provided by the very same engineers who build the technology.
            </p>
            <p>
                For more details and to take advantage of this unique opportunity please
                visit <a href="http://wso2.com/support">http://wso2.com/support</a>.
            </p>
            <p>
                For more information about WSO2 EI please see <a href="https://wso2.com/integration">
                http://wso2.com/products/enterprise-integrator</a>.
            </p>


            <p><i>-- The WSO2 EI Team --</i> </p>
        </div>
    </body>
</html>
